Preliminary Inventory to the Frank M. Surface Papers, 1915-1933
Hoover Institution Archives
Frank M. Surface Papers,
1915-1933
XX508
Surface, Frank Macy, 1882-1965
29 manuscript boxes, 2 cubic foot boxes, 1 oversize box 15 linear feet)
Hoover Institution Archives Stanford, California 94305-6010
Writings, correspondence, memoranda, reports, printed matter, and photographs, relating to regulation of the American economy, especially food products, during World War I; American Relief Administration activities; and postwar marketing of American commodities.
Administrative Information
Access
Collection open for research.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to sound recordings or to view videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Access Points
American Relief Administration.; United States. Dept. of Commerce.; United States. Food Administration.; United States Grain Corporation.; International relief.; World War, 1914-1918.; World War, 1914-1918--Civilian relief.; World War, 1914-1918--Economic aspects.; World War, 1914-1918--Food question.; World War, 1914-1918--United States.; United States--Politics and government.; United States--Foreign relations.; United States--Commerce.; United States--Economic conditions--1918-1945.; Hoover, Herbert, 1874-1964.
Container List
- Correspondence (Box 1.)
  - Bland
  - Elder, Robert E., Professor, regarding book "Marketing." Includes galleys
  - Fisher
  - Flesh, Edward, 1924-1931
  - Flesh Relief Report (Box 2.)
  - Hoover, Herbert, 1924-1926
  - Hoover, Herbert, including memoranda to H.H. from Surface, 1920 April
  - Rickard, Edgar
  - Sawtelle. Includes accounts
  - Taylor, Alonzo E.
  - American Relief Administration, 1927-1929. Includes miscellaneous correspondence
- Personal Correspondence
  - 1927
  - Miscellaneous. Includes preliminary report on Stanford School of Business, 1930 June, enclosed in letter to Hotchkiss, Dean W. E., 1930 July 17
  - Includes report on Stanford School of Business, 1931 August 31, enclosed in letter to Owen, Lillian, Miss, 1931 October 12
  - Miscellaneous. Includes Bell, James F., Harriman, E.H., Mrs., Heinz, and Hoover, Herbert (Box 3.)
- General
  - Literary Digest, Presidential Poll, 1928 November 3
  - Governor Smith's Campaign Speeches, 1928
  - Translation and summary by Edward Eyre Hunt of "A Picture of Political Parties in France," by Siegfried, André
  - Farm Relief Articles (Box 4.)
  - Food Administration Directory, 1920 January 8. Includes correspondence with former Food Administration members regarding date of joining and terminating for information concerning publishing a directory
  - Marketing Reports (Box 5.)
  - Annual Food Administration Report, 1918. Production of Meat in United States, 1919
  - Various reports
  - American Relief Administration Bulletins (Box 6.)
  - Report on Herbert Hoover's War Collection by E.D. Adams
- Oversize Boxes
  - Report of United States Grain Corporation to United States Senate, 1917 September - 1921 January 31 (Oversize 7.)
  - Tables of Imports into various countries
  - Grain Corporation Price Lists
  - 4 books on American Relief for Children in Austria, printed in German, 1921 (Oversize 8.)
  - Newspaper article "The City of Washington in 1822," The Washington Post, 1930
  - Colliers' Photographic History of the European War
  - Pork & Pork Products Charts
  - Stock Records Book
  - Reports
    - Meats, Dairy Products, and Vegetable Oils
    - Meats and Dairy Products
    - Feeds
    - Cereals
    - Vegetable Fats and Oils
    - Coffee and Sugar
    - Miscellaneous Agricultural Commodities
  - "Business and Economy," and "H. Hoover."Increment, 1974 (Oversize 9.)
    - Reports, memoranda, radio talks, and miscellaneous, by F. Surface, Julius Klein, and other, 1923-31, 1950
    - Monthly Crop Report, 1915-16 (3 issues)
    - Maps, postcards, photographs
    - Syndicated editorial articles by Dr. Frank M. Surface for the Washington Herald, 1920